So, Adjika Owens was laid to rest in Florida yesterday.
Adjika Owens is the mother of four who was brutally shot through the door by her neighbor
after she came to confront the neighbor for assaulting her children physically and verbally.
The neighbor cited the Stand Your Ground law.
On its surface, the Stand Your Ground law is simply self-defense.
In a state like Florida, where we know that racism drives the governance,
we know that the Stand Your Ground law, which was also used in George Zimmerman's case,
where he murdered Trayvon Martin,
is simply a cover for being able to take the lives of black people without having to be charged for it.
Because if someone's skin color is what makes them a weapon,
then just showing up as your black self is justification for someone to take a fatal effort
at defending themselves against your existence.
May Ms. Owens rest in peace.
And may we all continue to fight for the repeal of these types of laws
so that black people everywhere can live in peace.